Yomogi Kindergarten
Yes!
Kobato. Kobato!
Yes?
Can you read this?
Firefly's Light
Written by Sotaro Mori Drawings by Naoko Niimura
Firefly's Light...
Firefly's Light
Written by Sotaro Mori Drawings by Naoko Niimura
Please?! Read it for us!
Huh?
Kobato, don't tell us you can't read!
What?!
Of course I can read!
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
And when night fell, all became dark.
...Firefly Promise.
Even the moon was taking a rest.
Nothing is visible...
...but it is now visible.
Kobato, you skipped pages again!
What?!
Oh, I'm sorry. Um, Um... Agh!
Clumsy, as usual.
Huh?!
Hang in there Kobato!
Yes!
Good grief... Did she mess up again?
Yomogi Kindergarten, may I help you?
I thought I made it clear that the answer is "no".
Kindergarten is in session. Goodbye.
Kobato fell down again!
Your nose is all red!
I can't believe you fell again!
Dobato! It's not time to be fooling around.
Do - Ba - To -
There are issues at stake!
Bye-bye Kobato!
Yes, bye-bye.
Kobato, Kobato!
What is it, Marina?
Good luck in learning to read
the picture book well.
Yes, I'll do my best.
You'll be okay. I'm sure you'll
eventually get good at it.
Yes!
Um...
I'd like to practice so I can
make everyone happy.
May I borrow this?
Oh, uh... By all means.
I'm going to do my best so I can read better!
Mhm. Good luck with that.
Yes ma'am!
Firefly had been living all
alone for a long, long time.
It had been so long that Firefly had
completely forgotten that he was a firefly.
It must be lonely being alone.
Yeah, I guess.
I sort of recall something wonderful
happening on pitch dark nights like tonight.
Hey.
Did you want to talk to me?
Yeah. Would you stop that?
I'm asking you to quit reading that book.
Um... why is that?
Not a very nice type, is he?
What is it?
It's that guy again.
You're right.
What's up with him?
He seems totally different now.
I wonder if he's got something troubling him.
Excuse me!
Do you not have a place to live?!
How'd she come up with that?!
In fact, until just the other day, I too was
homeless and lived in the park too.
Then, thanks to Ms. Sayaka and Ms. Chisato,
I now get to sleep in a fluffy futon!
Futon mattresses are nice!
If it's okay with you, why not come to my home?
I don't plan to be taken in
by a complete stranger!
I'm Kobato Hanato! And this is Ioryogi-san!
I've had enough of you.
Um...
I wonder why he got angry with me.
Firefly saw a small pretty light in the distance.
Wondering what it was, he went closer...
I am clumsy, just like he said.
I'll do better tomorrow, for sure!
I slept in, again!
You're clumsy, whatever you do.
If you're late, Fujimoto will
be on your case again!
Wow! That's fast!
What?
Ah? What is it, little girl?
Good morning! May I help you?
Huh?
We're here to collect debt owed to us!
Huh? Debt?
Doesn't look very good.
Go on, eat it! I like little kids.
Come on!
Please stop that!
What do you think you're doing?!
You bump into me, and not
even a simple "I'm sorry"?
Well? Well?!
What the hell?! Get your hands off of me!
Don't you touch the kids!
Fujimoto!
Damn you!
Oww!
Who do you think you are?!
Stop it!
Ms. Sayaka.
I've asked you before not to come
while the kindergarten is open.
You've got the nerve to give us orders.
If you had paid your debts, this
wouldn't be happening, would it?
"Teacher."
Just because our boss is a nice man, don't you
be thinking you get special privileges.
I will speak with you after the
kindergarten is closed. So please...
We'll get out of here as soon as you
return what's owed to us. So...
Hurry and pay up!
Well?!
You...
What's she?
P-Please leave!
What the?
K-Kobato...
Please leave!
We don't have time to be playing
games with brats like you!
Please leave!
What is this girl?
Police officer!
Help! There are some scary men
here! Hurry and come!
We'll leave you alone today, but we'll
keep coming back until you pay!
Hey, let go of me!
Are you okay, Ms. Sayaka?
Yes, I'm fine.
Toshihiko!
Are you okay?
I was just faking it. I'm fine!
I thought they might leave if I said police.
Is that right? And they really did leave.
Good thinking!
Toshihiko, you were great!
That was nothing.
But if they ever come again,
I'll chase them away.
For a Dobato, you did a great job.
But how much longer do I have to stay like this?
So yesterday's call was from those guys.
Ms. Sayaka seemed troubled.
I wonder if there's anything I can do for her?
You don't have any money.
But maybe, she would feel better if
I were able to pay her debt off.
What is it?
Cashing
OK from 50,000 yen
Special offer campaign!!
Are you out of your mind?!
That guy...
There he is again. What's he doing?
What's this? Could he be?!
Excuse me!
Are you not feeling well?
I'm fine. It's nothing.
Um...
Isn't there anything I can do for you?
If something is troubling you...
Nothing is troubling me.
I have a house to go home to.
I just like being here. That's all.
I understand.
That book you had yesterday.
Oh, I borrowed this from the kindergarten.
I'm practicing but I'm not getting
much better at reading it.
I told you not to read it.
Why not? Everybody loves this story.
That's why I want to get good at reading it.
I'm begging you not to read it!
It's nothing.
Forget about it.
Does he really hate this book so much?
What are you doing here?
Because I live here.
You're my next door neighbor?!
Can't you tell?
Um!
What is it?
A guy at the park told me,
"don't read this picture book".
So you met Mr. Mori?
Mr. Mori?
What about Ioryogi-san?
No, I'm talking about the
guy who wrote the book.
Oh...
What?! Really?!
He's actually quite famous around here.
But, but, then why would he tell me
"don't read this picture book"?
I don't know.
But...
I did hear that he hasn't written a book since.
This was his last book?
Firefly's Light
Once upon a time there was a firefly, who
lived by the side of a beautiful stream.
Firefly's Light
Firefly had been living all
alone for a long, long time.
It had been so long that Firefly had
completely forgotten that he was a firefly.
One dark night, a night when the moon was not
out, Firefly saw a pretty light in the distance.
Wondering what it was, he went
closer and found a girl insect.
"You're very pretty. What kind of an
insect are you?" Firefly asked.
"I'm a firefly, just like you" she answered.
Then she said, "Why don't you
glow like the rest of us?"
Firefly had lived alone for so
long and forgot how to glow.
But seeing the sad expression on Firefly's face,
the little girl firefly taught him how to shine.
Ever since, the two spent days and nights
shining together by the riverside.
I guess the old man forgot how to shine too.
Who knows for what reason,
but just like the firefly in that book.
Isn't there anything we can do for him?
Nakayoshi Library
(Friendship Library)
Ecology of the Firefly
Japan Firefly Research Center
Hey, now what are you up to?
We're going to find it!
Huh?
Hey!
Are you free tonight?
Come and see the fireflies with me!
I'll be waiting for you in the forest of
Hachiman-yama, by the stream.
Firefly's memory came back. "I'm a firefly."
I can glow, just like you.
You've improved.
I'm sure he'll remember how to glow.
But... There's no sight of him.
You came!
Yeah, not that I really wanted to.
Oh, um... the fireflies...
they haven't shown up yet.
Why... did you say what you did?
"Come and see the fireflies with me. I'll be
waiting at Hachiman-yama, by the stream."
Those were the exact words
that Naoko said to me.
Naoko?
She was my love.
What?
Those pictures.
They're Naoko's drawings.
She suggested a story about
fireflies would be nice,
so I wrote the story and then
she drew the pictures.
Come and see the fireflies with me.
Come, let's go see the fireflies!
Remember? We promised.
Very well. I understand.
I don't have time.
Please don't say that.
I've found the perfect place.
I'm telling you, I don't have time.
I'll be waiting for you at
Hachiman-yama, by the stream.
Hello? Yes. Yes.
As it turned out, I wasn't able to go.
Those days, I was always busy.
I had many deadlines to meet.
So your girlfriend went alone.
"They were very beautiful."
"I would've liked for you to see
them, too", she told me.
Naoko's pictures always seemed so
lonely. But they were beautiful.
So that's why I decided to rewrite it
into a sad, yet beautiful story.
Then, some time after the book was completed...
Are you finally getting some time off?
Yeah. I'll meet you at the park.
Naoko. Hey, Naoko! Come on!
Sotaro?
Yeah, I'm right here.
Is there anything that you want?
I'll bring you whatever you'd like.
Fireflies...
What?
I wish... we could have seen
the fireflies together.
Why didn't I go with her then?
She wanted so badly to see them with me.
And yet I...
Why?
Let's go home.
P-Please wait!
Just a bit longer!
Just wait a bit longer and I'm sure...
Are you all right?
I-I'm sorry.
This place...
Naoko was standing right
here when she drew this.
Right here.
Fireflies...
Huh? You've never seen fireflies before?
So what? Anything wrong with that?
Then, come see them with me.
You've got to see them for yourself.
You won't find fireflies near here these days.
I'll show them to you. That's a promise.
It was a promise...
Wow!
They're pretty.
The fireflies.
They really are beautiful.
Yes.
Looks like the man's remembered how to glow.
He's started writing his next book, right?
And to prove that take a look at this.
There's more!
So what that means is...
That man was comforted.
So I was helpful to him.
So this time, I would like to give you
the entire one hundred points, but...
I am going to take away points for the
way you treated me at the library...
Kobato, eighty points!
Wow! Thank you so very much!
Don't lighten up. We're picking up the pace now!
Yes sir! Kobato is ready!
But then again, given the treatment you
gave me, eighty's a bit too generous.
Fifty's more like it.
No, no way! I much prefer 80.
Then, in that case...
Yes sir!
79 points.
What?! How'd you come up with that?!
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Hide and Seek.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Hide and Seek.